[
    {
        "question": "what are different types of Cisco OS's",
        "answer": "NX-OS IOS-XR IOS-XE",
        "notes": "NX-OS is the Cisco nexus data center IOS-XR runs on service provider routers IOS-XE runs on the ASR1000 of service provider routers",
        "mastery": -1
    },
    {
        "question": "What connection method is used when setting up a new device without an IP address configured to it yet",
        "answer": "CONSOLE CABLE",
        "notes": "The console cable (typically DB9 to RJ45) is used for the initial configuration",
        "mastery": -1
    },
    {
        "question": "Network device management question, What is the name for the network that is used just for managing network devices",
        "answer": "MANAGEMENT NETWORK",
        "notes": "The reason for separating the networks allows for a path to to the network devices if the Production network were to be down.",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Network management question: ___ management uses the Production network",
        "answer": "IN BAND",
        "notes": "in band management uses the production network, the band represents all traffic",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "New console cable connects USB to __-USB",
        "answer": "MINI",
        "notes": "The newer console cables dont use the DB9 as computers and laptops no longer have the physical port to connect to it. The USB portion is more compatible with newer PCs and the Mini USB is also compatible with newer network devices (USB C is newer ever still)",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Serial connection question, Speed",
        "answer": 9600,
        "notes": "The default speed of 9600 work for connecting using the serial connection in the network device console port",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Serial connection question, how many data bits",
        "answer": 8,
        "notes": "The default data bits are 8 for connecting using the serial connection in the network device console port",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Serial connection question, how many stop bits",
        "answer": 1,
        "notes": "The default stop bits are 1 for connecting using the serial connection in the network device console port",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Serial connection question, What is the parity set to",
        "answer": "NONE",
        "notes": "The default Parity is set to None as default for connecting using the serial connection in the network device console port",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Serial connection question, What is the Flow control set to",
        "answer": "NONE",
        "notes": "The default Flow control is set to None as default for connecting using the serial connection in the network device console port",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Console connection Troubleshooting: when connecting to a network device if connectin to the __ ____ does not work use the console cable",
        "answer": "IP ADDRESS",
        "notes": "If connecting using the IP address does not work try the console cable as a trouble shooting step",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Why would a network device not acquire an IP address",
        "answer": "NOT BOOTING UP",
        "notes": "If the network device fails to start up then there will be no IP address to connect to, using the console connection you can view the boot up process and the error messages when it fails to boot up.",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "what is the IOS command used to view all the commands that are available in the command hierarchy",
        "answer": "?",
        "notes": "The question mark (?) is used to list all the available commands in the command lines current command hierarchy",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the level 1 in the command line hierarchy. __ exec mode",
        "answer": "USER",
        "notes": "USER exec mode is the first level when logging into the Cisco IOS",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What commands takes you from User Exec to Privilege exec mode",
        "answer": "ENABLE",
        "notes": "The enable keyword goes up a level in the command line hierarchy",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the level 2 in the command line hierarchy. __ exec mode",
        "answer": "PRIVILEGE",
        "notes": "Privilege exec mode is the level 2 command line hierarchy in Cisco IOS",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What command takes you from Privilege mode into User mode",
        "answer": "DISABLE",
        "notes": "the Disable command allows you to exit privilege exec mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(mode question) Router>",
        "answer": "USER EXEC",
        "notes": "The device name followed by '>' signifies USER EXEC mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(command abbreviation)Router>en",
        "answer": "ENABLE",
        "notes": "en is shortened version of the ENABLE command",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "the SHOW command is a part of this command hierarchy",
        "answer": "PRIVILEGE EXEC",
        "notes": "the show command is typically ran through the PRIVILEGE EXEC mode, it could be run in higher level command modes with the DO command 'DO SHOW'",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "from PRIVILIGE EXEC what command will switch mode into a configure mode",
        "answer": "CONFIGURE TERMINAL",
        "notes": "The configure Terminal command, will enter the configuration mode from PRIVILIGE EXEC mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a shortened command for CONFIGURE TERMINAL",
        "answer": "CONF T",
        "notes": "conf t command is the shortened version for CONFIGURE TERMINAL",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(mode question)Router(config)#",
        "answer": "GLOBAL CONFIGURATION",
        "notes": "The device name followed by '(config)#' signifies global configuration mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Shortcut Question: Using command history which keyboard shortcut will take you to the start of the command to add commands at the start of the line:Answer format: Ctrl _",
        "answer": "Ctrl A",
        "notes": "Ctrl A allows you to go the start of the command to type from the beginning of the line",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Fix this command: Router1(config)#show ip interface brief",
        "answer": "do show ip interface brief",
        "notes": "The do command allows for the use of the show command outside of Privilege exec mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "enter interface configuration level for fastEthernet 0/0: Router1(config)#",
        "answer": "interface fastEthernet 0/0",
        "notes": "The interface command allows you to enter into interface configuration mode. You can view available interfaces on the router using command: show ip interface brief",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(Command question) which command leaves interface config mode and global config mode",
        "answer": "exit",
        "notes": "similar to disable Privilege exec mode, exit goes down a command hierarchy level from both interface and global configuration modes",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "True or false: can you go directly into interace configuration mode from Privilege exec mode mode",
        "answer": "false",
        "notes": "In order to interface configuration mode you must go into global configuration mode first. You cannot skip a command line hierarchy level",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Besides Ctrl C which command will leave from both global and interface configuration modes into privilege exec mode",
        "answer": "end",
        "notes": "While the exit command takes you back one level, the end command will leave configuration mode all together back into Privilege exec mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Besides the show interface brief command, which command is the most popular show commad",
        "answer": "show running-config",
        "notes": "the show running-config command is a very popular command that shows the currently running configuration",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Besides the show running-config command which command is the most popular show command",
        "answer": "show interface brief",
        "notes": "The show interface brief command is a very popular command that shows the status of the routers interfaces as well as any IP addresses configured to the ports",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(command abbreviation question): Router1# show running-config interface fastEthernet 0/0",
        "answer": "sh run int f0/0",
        "notes": "This shortened command will display part of the running config, since the output can be so extensive, in a shortened form with only information regarding the fastEthernet 0/0",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(command w/ abbreviation question) use a pipe to begin the running-configuration at the section where hostnames start",
        "answer": "sh run | begin hostname",
        "notes": "This command uses a pipe to run extra arguments. Beginning with the line that matches hostname. arguments after the pipe (|) are case sensitive",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(mode question)Which command line mode allows you to use the copy command",
        "answer": "privilege exec",
        "notes": "the privilege exec mode (enable) allows you to use the copy command",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(command question w abbreviation)Which command copies the current running config into a tftp server",
        "answer": "copy run tftp",
        "notes": "Copying the running configuration into a tftp server is a better way to save a configuration rather than storing it into the routers flash as it is a single point of weakness",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "which command allows you to view a configuration saved into flash memory",
        "answer": "more",
        "notes": "The more command will output the configuration saved into the devices flash memory. #more flash:config1 will show the configuration stored in config1",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(memory question)where is the IOS Operating system image stored",
        "answer": "flash",
        "notes": "The IOS OS image is stored in flash memory",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(memory question)where is the Starup configuration stored",
        "answer": "NVRAM",
        "notes": "The starup configuration is stored in NVRAM",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(memory question)where is the Running configuration stored",
        "answer": "RAM",
        "notes": "The Running configuration is sored in RAM",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(memory question)What is the difference between NVRAM and RAM",
        "answer": "persistence",
        "notes": "NVRAM is nonvolatile meaning that it retains data even if there is a break in the power supply. Normal RAM requires constant power from the power supply to store the data. NVRAM can hold the data persistently with an NVRAM battery",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(mode question) Router#",
        "answer": "PRIVILEGE EXEC",
        "notes": "The device name followed by '#' signifies PRIVILEGE EXEC mode",
        "mastery": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "(command question) complete the command to show available argmuents after the pipe section of the command sh run |",
        "answer": "sh run | ?",
        "notes": "Similar to the normal IOS command line the question mark (?) allows you to view available commands",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "(command question)How would you save the routers current configuration using the copy command",
        "answer": "copy running-config startup-config",
        "notes": "To save the current configuration into the startup-config you could use the copy command under privilege exec mode to copy the running config into the startup config with this command",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Network management question: ___ management uses the management network",
        "answer": "OUT OF BAND",
        "notes": "Out of band management uses the dedicated management network to manage the network devices",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Command line interface for SECURELY connecting to the devices management IP address over the network",
        "answer": "SSH",
        "notes": "SSH is a secure way to connect to the command line interface over the network",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "When using Windows under Device Manager, what is the name of the port for the serial connection",
        "answer": "COM",
        "notes": "The COM port is used for the serical connections and used in PuTTY to connect the COM port # to the network device",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "UNSECURE way to connect to a network devices command line interface",
        "answer": "TELNET",
        "notes": "Telnet is supported but not reccomended",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the server that enforces secure logins through this centralized server",
        "answer": "AAA SERVER",
        "notes": "Enterprises will user (AAA) Authentication, Authorization, and Accounting server for secure login to network devices.",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Name of popular client used to connect to network devices",
        "answer": "PUTTY",
        "notes": "PuTTY is a client used to connect to network devices over serial, Telnet, and SSH",
        "mastery": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Network device management question, What is the name for the network that all traffic goes through from a network engineer point of view",
        "answer": "PRODUCTION NETWORK",
        "notes": "The production network is the network path that non network devices use, network management could also use this type of network engineers may also use a completely different network for managing Network Devices",
        "mastery": 1
    }
]